Hey! This video is going to tell you a little bit about
each section in this course, so you get a good idea of what
we're going to cover.
First, after you get the pre-requirements, like making sure
you have a compatible operating system, making sure you
download the course repo, stuff like that, we'll get into
the installation details of Docker itself.
Docker Desktop works on Mac and Windows 10,
and that's really the best thing to do.
But, there's lots of other details in there about whether
you're using Linux, or an old Windows version, or you just
want to use a server on the Internet.
Then we jump into the Docker basics around
how do you run containers? What is a container?
What's in it? What's not in it?
Running some examples.
Then we learn how to build the images, which are the
building blocks of containers, and you go through some
examples of that.
Then I go into details and examples around networking for
Docker and how that works.
Then maybe some of the storage stuff that you're going to
deal with called Volumes.
Then, we get into Docker Compose, which is a tool that
comes with Docker, but it really is designed for local
Dev and Test, and it's great.
I use it every day when I'm working on projects.
Then, after you understand all of the basics of those
tools, we start talking about orchestration, which is
allowing you to run containers on multiple servers that act
sort of like a single server.
We first start out with Swarm because it comes with Docker
out-of-the-box. It's very easy to understand, and it works
really great in a lot of scenarios.
You'll learn about YAML files and how to configure
multi-container solutions, and distributed systems,
and micro services and all that.
Eventually, you'll want to jump into Kubernetes, which
comes after Swarm.
I teach Swarm before Kubernetes because I think it's a good
stepping stone because Kubernetes is so much more
complicated and does so much more than Swarm.
But, Swarm is easy to understand, so it's a great first
step. I think all of us really need to learn at least
two orchestrators since there's now, I don't know, four or
five, six, at least common ones out there.
Obviously, Kubernetes gets a lot of the market share and
mindshare, but it's not the only solution, and it sometimes
is more complicated than you need.
So, it's good to have multiple tools in your toolset.
That's why I teach both in this course.
Then I finish up the course with a bunch of various things
related to all these topics. Things like student's common
questions and answers, maybe some live stuff
from my YouTube show where students show up and ask
questions about topics in the course that aren't heavily
covered, so I give you some more details on that.
Then, I actually review some student real-world
Docker and Compose files and sort of break them down,
talk about what's good about them, what's bad about them,
so that you can learn from other people's work.
Of course, throughout the whole course, there are tons and
tons of references. Anywhere I can, I put links to
documentation or really good blog posts that I,
or someone else, has made on a topic so you can get further
reading. Then, near the end of the course, I start to give
you jumping off points in case you want to take one of my
other courses that goes into more detail on that topic,
like Swarm Mastery, or maybe Node.js for
Docker, or my forthcoming Kubernetes course.
Obviously, no single course is going to solve
all of your problems and have all the answers.
Along with the Slack Chat, and the YouTube,
and the Podcast, and the newsletter, and the Q&A, and
everything else that we do to try to help you learn these
container tools, you're going to get your questions
answered, one way or another.
Of course, the nice thing about the Slack community is
there's tons of people in there that are happy to help you,
who have a wide range of backgrounds, and it's really
great. I'm really excited that we've had a lot of people
stick around over the years and build that community with
us. Thanks for watching.
I'll see the next video.